准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
出卖
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
他们来了  小子们
Here they come, lads
万岁
Hooray
太棒了
Fantastic
非常感谢  女士
Thank you very much, madam
我好有活力
I feel so alive
财富财富  发财致富
Cha-ching, cha-ching, cha-chingaree
金钱金钱  我好爱你
Money, oh, money, how I love thee
财富财富  发财致富
Cha-ching, cha-chong, cha-changaroo
从分到元  多少都行
From pennies to dollars any amount'll do
财富财富  没有角逐
Cha-ching, cha-ching, it's no contest
我最爱的  只有一个东西
There's only one thing that I love the best
从看到的壮丽景象
From every sight I've ever seen
到听见的美妙天籁
To the sweetest sound I've heard
我乐意放弃掉一切
I'd gladly give up everything
不惜代价赚到钱
For all the money that I've earned
财富财富  发财致富
Cha-ching, cha-ching, cha-chingaree
世上一切  比不过贪心
There's nothing on earth like the feeling of greed
世上一切
There's nothing on earth
比不过贪心
Like the feeling of greed
不要再那样了
Please don't do that again
我看彩色玻璃高脚凳可以放这
I think the stained-glass barstool can go over here
麂皮手工雕刻木制运动旗帜展示柜
and the pseudo hand-carved
wooden sports flag display case
可以放那里
can go over there
三位你们好
Ahoy there, matey
需要给你们什么服务吗
Can I help you gentlemen with something?
我要跟店主谈谈
I'd like to speak to the owner
你们算老几
Who wants to know?
容我自我介绍
Allow me to introduce myself
霍华德白兰地  白兰地经销公司总裁
Howard Blandy, President
of the Blandy Franchising Company
霍华德白兰地
Howard Blandy
你是说那个霍华德白兰地
You mean the Howard Blandy?
就是那个策划进行无情接管
The Howard Blandy
that masterminded the ruthless takeover
裤头村所有个体经营餐厅的那个
of every small, family-owned business in Bikini Bottom?
那个霍华德白兰地
That Howard Blandy?
我好崇拜你
I worship you
振作起来  小伙
Get it together a little, man
抱歉  单纯只是
Sorry, it's just that
你富得流油
you're rich
我是蟹老板
I'm Mr. Krabs
是什么风把你吹来蟹堡王的  霍华德
To what do I owe the honor
of having you at the Krusty Krab, Howard?
从你这收购蟹堡王要出多少价
What would it take to buy the Krusty Krab from you?
收购蟹堡王
Buy the Krusty Krab?
蟹堡王不是拿来卖的
It's not for sale
虽然我可能搞不出来你那种
You know, I may not make as much
奢侈得要死的那种连锁餐厅
as your fancy-schmancy mega restaurant chain
但这是整天辛劳的血汗与泪水的结晶
but it's the blood, sweat and tears of a hard day's work
可不是给点
It's not about the
珍珍的妈啊
Holy sweet mother of pearl
我好喜欢你的思考方式  白兰地
I like the way you think, Blandy
可这一手提箱的钱还不够
But it'll take a lot more than a suitcase full of cash
可没法从我手上买走蟹堡王
to buy the Krusty Krab from me
钱还有不少
There's a lot more than that
剩下的在那边
The rest is over there
我的海神王啊
Jumping King Neptune
成交  能拿钱了吗
Sold, can I have my money?
只有一个条件  签订这份合同
Just one thing, if you can sign this contract
表明你转让蟹堡王以及其所有权
It just states that you relinquish the Krusty Krab
and all ownership thereof
还有其员工  商品
along with its employees, merchandise
商标  收银机
logos and cash registers
我还能拿到钱吗
I still get the money?
当然
Of course
那样就好
That'll be fine then
拿去吧
Here you go
快给我给我给我给我
Now, give me, give me, give me, give me
再见了
See you 'round
怎么回事
What's happening?
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
蟹老板  他们在蟹堡王挂三角旗
Mr. Krabs, they're putting up pennants in the Krusty Krab
是怎么回事
What's going on?
我要退休了
I'm retiring
退休了
Retiring?
我可以想做什么就做什么
I'm free to do whatever I want
可以学骑我30年前买的自行车
I can learn how to ride that bicycle I got 30 years ago
或者去逛市中心新开的鱼钩博物馆
Or go to the new hook museum downtown
还可以画碗装的水果
Or ever paint bowls of fruit
你们不该替我高兴吗
Aren't you happy for me?
我好高兴
I sure am
再见了  小子们
So long, boys
祝你开心  蟹老板
Have fun, Mr. Krabs
天都知道我不会替他高兴
Heaven knows I won't
两位好
Hi, gentlemen
我是卡尔  你们的新经理
I'm Carl, I'll be your new manager
新经理
New manager?
你们在周一蟹堡工作的工作体验
I think you'll find working at the Krabby O'Mondays
必定会寓教于乐
to be both a learning experience and an enjoyable one
周一蟹堡
Krabby O'Mondays?
这些玩意再也用不着了
You won't need these anymore
这是你们的新制服
Now, here are your new uniforms
然后这是
and here are the
员工手册
employee manuals
明天早上再见
See you first thing tomorrow
全新一天的甜美香气
The sweet smell of a brand new day
第一站  新开的鱼钩博物馆
First stop, the new hook museum
周一蟹堡
然后我就
Then maybe I'll
周一蟹堡
The Krabby O'Mondays?
我才不取这种名字
Not the name I would've chosen
不过都已经过去了
But that's all behind me now
鱼钩博物馆
本地水域发现J形三叉鱼钩的时间
The three-pronged J hook
was first sighted in local water
早于一百多年以前
more than one hundred years ago
等一下
Wait a minute
我讨厌高尔夫
I hate golf
行了  我想做的事情全都做完了
Well, I've done everything I wanted to do
结果连中午都还没到
and it's not even noon
你看到她穿的鞋了吗
Did you see the shoes she had on?
太过时了
So last-year
先别挂  吉娜
Hold on, Gina
爸  什么事
Yeah, Dad?
你好吗
How's it going?
好得很
Fine
你在干嘛
What're you up to?
我在打电话
I'm talking on the phone
是吗
Really?
没错
Really
爸  你就没有正事要干吗
Dad, isn't there something you need to do?
其实我希望
Well, actually I was hoping
能跟你一起做点什么
you and I could do something together
滚出去
Get out
给我得了  爸
That's it, Dad
去找工作  找爱好
Get a job, get a hobby
要么就找朋友
or get some friends
反正我再也受不了了
because I can't take it anymore
她说要找朋友
Get some friends, she says
她说要找爱好
Find a hobby, she says
她说要找工作
Get a job, she says
招聘
"Help Wanted"
周一蟹堡
三位你们好
Ahoy there, mateys
欢迎光临周一蟹堡
Welcome to the Krabby O'Mondays
今天我生日
It's my birthday
我能先开始给你们
Can I start you off with
你可以唱周一蟹堡生日歌
Will you sing the Krabby Monday's birthday song
给我的小寿星听吗
to my special little man?
生日生日快乐
Happy, happy birthday
生日生日快
Happy, happy
章鱼哥
Squidward?
能跟你单独谈谈吗
Can I talk to you for a second?
我们周一蟹堡的座右铭是什么
What's our motto here at Krabby O'Mondays?
真诚服务  面带微笑
"Sincere service with a smile"
没错
Well, yes
不过也要有周一蟹堡精神
but with the Krabby O'Mondays spirit
章鱼哥啊  你该不会
Now, Squidward, you wouldn't want
想跟人事部那边的谈谈吧
to have to talk to Human Resources
对吧
would you?
那么座右铭是什么呢
So, what's our motto again?
真诚服务
Sincere service
面带微笑
with a smile
这下你可算会了
Now you're getting it
早安  海绵宝宝
Morning, SpongeBob
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
你来这干什么
What are you doing here?
退休到头来也没好到哪去
Retirement ain't all it's cracked up to be
所以我就来当洗碗工了
so I'm the new busboy
行了  小子
Okay, son
你可要吓坏我了
you're starting to creep me out
我就知道你会回来  蟹老板
I knew you'd come back, Mr. Krabs
我就知道
I just knew you would
小子  继续工作吧
Okay, boy, back to work
遵命  老板
Aye-aye, sir
我再也不是你老板了
I'm not your boss anymore
叫我尤金就好
Just call me Eugene
遵命
Aye-aye
尤金
Eugene
你好  章鱼哥
Ahoy, Squidward
你好  尤金
Ahoy, Eugene
你介意帮我擦一下桌子吗
Would you mind clearing this table for me?
行啊  章鱼哥
Sure, Squidward
知道不  我从来没看过你这么高兴
You know, I've never seen you so happy
我们被监视了
They're watching us
那家伙就是很讨厌  对吧章鱼哥
That guy's a real pain in the hindquarters, hey, Squiddy?
尤金  我觉得你要再看下
Eugene, I think you need to look
员工手册的第20页
at page 20 of our employee handbook again
我才用不着卡尔定的笨规矩
I don't need Carl's silly rules
我真的觉得你应该要看一下
I really think you should look
救命
这什么啊
What's this?
救命
"Help me"
各位啊  这边是怎么回事
Hey, fellas, what's going on over here?
卡尔啊
Hey, Carl
我只是在提醒尤金
I was just reminding Eugene
员工手册的第24条第3款
of article 24, section three of the employee handbook
少说话  多上菜
"Cut the chatter and pick up a platter"
干得漂亮  章鱼哥
Good job, Squidward
你对真正的章鱼哥动了什么手脚
What have you done with the real Squidward?
尤金  你知道得越少
The less you know, Eugene
就越好
the better
这边是怎么一回事
What's going on around here?
海绵宝宝哪去了
Where's SpongeBob?
合成堡
注意
上菜
爱哪去了
Where's the love?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
蟹黄堡怎么了
What happened to the Krabby Patties?
我尽力跟他们说了
I tried to tell them
可他们就是不听
but they wouldn't listen to me
简直下流
This is obscene
卡尔
Carl
我要跟你谈
I need to have a word
您的零钱是一块七毛五
Your change is $1.75
自动收银机
Automated cash register?
不要
No
卡尔  你对我餐厅都干了些什么
Hey, Carl, what have you done with me restaurant?
加工过的蟹黄堡  计算机化的收银机
Processed Krabby Patties, computerized registers
看看你这周围
Look around you
我们的客人很满足于
Our customers are quite content
这种不自然  这种中规中矩
with the contrived and the mediocre
那是因为他们不知道
That's because they don't know
自己是在吃什么
what they're eating
不好意思  美女
Excuse me, ma'am
知不知道你吃的蟹黄堡里有什么
do you know what's in that Krabby Patty you're eating?
不知道
No
看见没
See that?
没了你那种障眼法
Without all your smoke and mirrors
根本就没有人会吃这种垃圾
no one would stomach this garbage
他说什么
What'd he say?
垃圾
Garbage?
尤金  你己经违约了
Eugene, you're in violation of your contract
规矩是吧
Rules
给你一条规矩
Here's a rule for you
不能让人吃彩色玻璃高脚凳
people can't eat stained-glass barstools
给你看看什么叫自动
I'll show you automated
白兰地先生  红色警报
Mr. Blandy, code red--
自由思想家
free thinker
蟹老板  这里有什么问题
Mr. Krabs, is there a problem here?
你最好要相信有问题
You better believe there's a problem
我从前会亲吻你走过的地面  白兰地
I used to kiss the ground you walked on, Blandy
可看到这一幕之后
but after seeing this
我连痰都不屑朝你那边吐
I wouldn't even spit in your direction
蟹黄堡应该要亲手
Krabby Patties are supposed to be made by hand--
一个一个做
one at a time--
合成堡
不是搁传送带上做
not on a conveyer belt
天啊
Oh, my
所以我是不是不能加薪了  老板
Does this mean I won't get that raise, sir?
全毁了
It's ruined
只好把它卖掉了
We'll have to sell it
能回一点点本都能算运气好了
We'll be lucky if we get a fraction of what we paid for it
我要以全价买下蟹堡王
I'll buy it for full price
成交
Sold
再也用不着你的合同了
We won't need your contract anymore
很高兴跟您一起做生意
Nice doing business with you
我倍感荣幸
Pleasure's all mine
给我滚出我的餐厅
Now get out of me restaurant
成功了  小子们
Well, we did it, boys
蟹堡王又回到我们手上了
The Krusty Krab is ours again
要知道  我发了这么一场怒
You know, in that fit of maniacal rage
可能毁掉了蟹堡王
I may have destroyed the restaurant,
吓跑了所有的客人  逼到我们破产
scared away all our customers
and forced us into bankruptcy--
因为卖这破店的钱基本还回去了
because I returned
nearly every penny I sold this stink-heap for--
但这一切都很值得
but it was all worth it
而且我又重新得到了好朋友的爱
and I got back the love of me dear friends
真的吗  蟹老板
Really, Mr. Krabs?
错  不完全真
No, not really
回去工作
Get back to work
爱笑海绵
分镜总监
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
章鱼哥
Squidward
你想搞什么  海绵宝宝
What do you want, SpongeBob?
上班时间到了  章鱼哥
Time for work, Squidward
新的一天也要挣钱
Another day, another dollar
挣几个子还差不多
More like another nickel
真好笑  章鱼哥
Good one, Squidward
新的一天也要挣几个子
Another day, another nickel
没那么好笑
It's not that funny
蟹堡王
因为真实  所以好笑
That's funny because it's true
便车搭完了
Carpool's over
几个子
Nickel
你的餐来了
Here's your food
没那么好笑
It's not that funny
求你快住嘴
Please make it stop
开
关
章鱼哥  明天见
Okay, Squidward, see you tomorrow
时刻检查零钱
And always check for spare change
新的一天也要挣
Another day, another
几个子
nickel
两份蟹黄堡
Two Krabby Patties
谢了小子
Thanks, kid
新的一天也要挣几个子
Another day, another nickel
别笑了  折磨精
Cease your laughing, tormentor
机会来了
This could be my chance
海绵宝宝  你看起来很不舒服
SpongeBob, you don't look well
我不舒服
I don't?
没错
No
你应该要坐下
You should sit down
可
But
你发烧了  海绵宝宝
You're burning up, SpongeBob
真的吗
I am?
海绵宝宝  你跟我说
Tell me, SpongeBob
你身子侧面疼不疼
have your sides been hurting?
是有点
Yeah, a little
94摄氏度
你体温居然有175度了
And your temperature is 175 degrees
那是坏事吗
Is that bad?
不是不是不是
Oh, no, no, no, no, no
除非你最近老是
unless you've been doing a lot of
笑
laughing
我最近确实老是笑
I have been laughing a lot lately
海绵宝宝  你必须要小心点
SpongeBob, you've got to be careful
不然会把笑声囊烧坏的
You're going to burn out your laughbox
笑声囊
My laughbox?
没错  那是你的身体部位
Yes, it's the part of your body
可以让你发出笑声
that enables laughter
要是长期过度不停使用
If you use it too long without giving it a break
就会发烧  然后你就再也笑不出来了
it burns out and you can never laugh again
你就是这样的吗  章鱼哥
Is that what happened to you, Squidward?
没错
Yes
什么
What?
不对
No
海绵宝宝你听好
Listen, SpongeBob
情况很严重
this is serious
要是把笑声囊烧伤了
If you burn out your laughbox
你这辈子就再也笑不出来了
you'll live your whole life
without ever laughing again
派大星  想不想听个笑话
Hey, Patrick, you want to hear a joke?
好啊  珊迪
Sure, Sandy
好啊  我要大笑一阵子
Sure, I'd love a good laugh
有 苍 蝇
有四个轮子还会飞的是什么
What has four wheels and flies?
垃圾车
A garbage truck
可不能把我笑声囊烧伤了  章鱼哥
I don't want to burn out my laughbox, Squidward
最重要的事情就是不要再笑了
Well, the most important thing is to stop laughing
任何一种笑都可能会很危险
Any laugh at all could be dangerous
必须要不笑多久才行
How long do I have to avoid laughing?
天啊  海绵宝宝
Gosh, SpongeBob
至少应该要后半天都不笑
I'd say at least the rest of the day
不过你最好要24小时不笑保平安
but you better go 24 hours just to be safe
太谢谢你了  章鱼哥
Thank you so much, Squidward
没你我都不知道要咋办
I don't know what I'd do without you
一整天不笑只是一点小小的代价
A day without laughter is a small price to pay
这样才能保护笑声囊不被彻底摧毁
to save my laughbox from utter destruction
必须要时刻警惕
I must remain vigilant
那边没有好笑的东西
Nothing funny over there
这边没有好笑的东西
Nothing funny over here
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
最近过得怎样
How's it going?
派大星
Patrick--
香蕉皮
banana peel--
别
don't
你刚说什么
What did you say?
不好
Oh, no
怎么
What the
等一下  派大星
Wait a minute, Patrick
住脚
Please stop
先走右脚
Right foot first
等等
Wait
派大星  我不能笑的
Patrick, I can't laugh
不能吗
You can't?
我知道要怎么办了
I know what to do
平常这样明明能笑翻他的
That usually knocks him out
控制住自己  海绵宝宝
Get a grip on yourself, SpongeBob
你控制得住
You're in control
离放屁坐垫远一点  海绵宝宝
Just back away from the whoopie cushion, SpongeBob
到处都是
They're everywhere
都是
Everywhere
放屁坐垫
小心那辆装派的卡车
Look out for that pie truck
派
一定要逃走
I've got to get out of here
正在驶离裤头村
这边没有好笑的东西
There's nothing funny up here
可为了安全起见
But just to be safe
我已经成功实现24小时不笑了
I made it 24 hours without laughing
好奇怪
That's odd
我笑不出来了
I've lost my laugh
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
太可怕了  派大星
It's terrible, Patrick--
我再也不能笑了
I can't laugh anymore
怎么回事
What happened?
我一天都没有笑
I went a whole day without laughing
现在我就笑不出来了
and now my laugh is gone
我来看一下
Let me take a look
里面好黑
It's dark in here
得点根火柴
I'd better light a match
蟹堡王
请进
Come in
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs?
怎么了  小子
What's wrong, boy?
我笑不出来了
I lost my laugh
那你就来对地方了  小子
You've come to the right place, son
有样东西总能让我笑得出来
You know, there's one thing that always makes me laugh
你看它不觉得好笑吗  小子
Don't it just tickle you, boy?
不大觉得
Not really
看来得用极端措施
This calls for drastic measures
我平时一般不会这么做
I don't usually do this
可你好像很迫切需要
but you seem desperate
摸吧
Touch it
没变
Nothing
比我想的还要糟
This is worse than I thought
毕竟钱可是欢乐的终极源头
After all, money is the ultimate source of joy
也许应该要去问珊迪
Maybe I should ask Sandy
她是科学家
She's a scientist
用科学来处理就简单了  海绵宝宝
It's easy if you approach it scientifically, SpongeBob
什么是笑声
Now, what is laughter?
它曾向我的一生给予意义和目标
The thing that used to give my life meaning and purpose
可现在却在用冷酷无情来嘲弄我
but now mocks me with its cruel indifference
可是从科学上来讲  之所以会笑
But scientifically speaking, it's caused by
是因为会厌导致你的喉咙收紧
your epiglottis constricting your larynx
使得进气不规则而呼吸紊乱
causing irregular air intake and respiratory upset
听起来好疼
Sounds painful
科学会让一切都听起来疼  海绵宝宝
Science makes everything sound painful, SpongeBob
送你一点幽默理论课本
Now, here's some humor-theory textbooks
大笑力学  还有量子傻笑理论
laugh mechanics and the quantum giggle theory
谢谢  珊迪
Thank you, Sandy
这下倒是安静多了
Sure is peaceful around here
毕竟海绵宝宝变得不中用了
since SquarePants became a sad sack
我书都看完了  还是没变
I've read all the books, and still nothing
我应该再也笑不出来了
I guess I'll never laugh again
我真不想看到那小子难过
I really hate to see the little guy so sad
可我更不想看人家高兴
but not as much as I hate to see him happy
之后在同一天晚上
发现比起他笑声更难听的东西了
I think I found the one thing I hate more than his laugh
迟早能哭累他
I'm sure he'll cry himself out soon
我都干了些什么
What have I done?
够了
That's it
这场把戏必须要结束了
This charade has to end
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
海绵宝宝  别鬼哭狼嚎了
SpongeBob, this infernal crying has to stop
可章鱼哥  我
But Squidward, I
我伤到了笑声囊
I broke my laughbox
海绵宝宝  根本就没有笑声囊这玩意
SpongeBob, there's no such thing as a laughbox
都是我编出来的
I made the whole thing up
这样你才不会瞎笑  我才能静一静
to get some peace from your insipid laughter
你是说我的笑声囊没被伤到
You mean my laughbox isn't broken?
你完全就是存心骗我
And it was a cruel lie
害我一下子抑郁过去吗
that sent me into spiraling depression?
你这么说好像确实挺残忍  不过
Yeah, well, it sounds pretty harsh
when you put it that way, but
没错
yeah
我一直都可以笑吗
I could laugh the whole time?
对
Yeah
你上当了
You really fell for it
我看是没错
I guess I did
连体温计泡热油那套都能让你上当
You even fell
for the old thermometer-in- the-boiling-oil routine
真的没那么好笑  章鱼哥
It's not really that funny, Squidward
笑死我了
It's hilarious
再见  章鱼哥
See you later, Squidward
弄伤笑声囊
Break your laughbox
真是个傻子
What a schlemiel
看  他醒过来了
Look, he's waking up
我在哪
Where am I?
你住院了  笨蛋
You're in the hospital, silly
你把笑声囊弄伤了
You broke your laughbox
医生说这笑声囊最小最干
The doctor said it was the most tiny, dried out
利用最不充分  行医生涯中前所未见
underused laughbox he'd ever laid eyes on
所以医生就割了
So they cut it out
割了
Cut it out?
没错
Yeah
要看吗
Want to see it?
摇一摇看它弹来弹去还挺好玩的
It's fun to shake it up and watch it bounce around
给我
Give me
我再也笑不出来了吗
I can never laugh again?
才不会呢
Nonsense--
你应该能笑得更厉害了
your laugh should be stronger than ever
可你们明明把我笑声囊割了啊
But you cut out my laughbox
没错  但你一位朋友慷慨地让我们
Yes, but one of your friends has generously allowed us
把自己的笑声囊移植一部分给你
to transplant part of theirs to you
不是我
Nope
医生不给钱
They wouldn't pay me
离答案越来越近了
You're getting warmer
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
你笑得好像我
You laugh just like me
他去跟这个世界共享欢笑了
There he goes, off to share his laughter with the world